ラジオ絵会はハートでつかめ英語の極一行詞のお西ひろとです
さあ金曜復習会頑張っていきましょう
それでは早速始めていきましょう
今週のリビュー金曜日は復習会です
最初のコーナーはこちら
OK, let's review this week's dialogues
Listen to the questions and pick which one of the three options is the correct answer
Let's start with Monday's dialogue
Here's the question
Who finally pays for dinner?
A. The woman
B. The man
Or C. Both of them
Here we go
Anyway, that was a delicious meal, sir.
Thanks for recommending it.
I'm glad you enjoyed it.
Oh, oh no.
What's wrong?
We don't have any cash from this country.
How are we going to pay for this?
Take it easy.
I don't want you to feel bad.
I will pay for it.
But it's expensive.
A steak dinner and we had two ales.
It's on me this time.
They don't take credit cards, do they?
What is a credit card?
Aww
Were you able to understand?
Let's go over the question one more time
Who finally pays for dinner?
A. The woman
B. The man
Or C. Both of them
答えは?
B. The man
質問は結局誰がディナーの支払いをする?
A. 誰が支払いをする?
女性 b 男性 c 二人とも
答えは b 男性となります
alright now let's move on to tuesday's dialogue here's the question
which of the following is true
a jessica sent some messages to professor peacock
b jessica saw professor peacock taking the time capsule home
or c. jessica wants to know about the letter in the time capsule listen up
hello jessica sorry to keep you waiting hello professor peacock no worries
i was just checking some messages did you have a question for me today
yes it's about that time capsule at your home oh you saw me taking it home
No, but I heard there was a letter inside.
Oh, really? Who told you that?
I don't remember. Is it true?
Yes, there was an old letter.
Who wrote it?
Jessica, we are not sure yet.
Okay, how did you do?
Let's check out that question one more time.
Which of the following is true?
a. jessica sent some messages to professor peacock
b. jessica saw professor peacock taking the time capsule home
c. jessica wants to know about the letter in the time capsule
答えは
質問は次のうち正しいのは
a. jessicaはピーコック教授にメッセージを何通か送った
b.
ジェシカはピーコック教授がタイムカプセルを家に持ち帰るところを見た
スイ ジェシカはタイムカプセルの中の手紙について知りたい
答えはスイ ジェシカはタイムカプセルの中の手紙について知りたいとなります
次はウェンズデイのダイアログです
質問です
女性はジョナスをどうしたらいいのか
A. コーヒーを買う
b. do a presentation next week
or c. make slides before noon
listen carefully
morning jonas do you have a minute
sure i was just about to take a coffee break
good i need your help with something
you are asking me for help
yes i'm pretty busy right now
you made the slides for the presentation last week yeah
yeah that was me
Can you make slides for this document?
Sure. It doesn't look that difficult.
I'll have it done by 5 o'clock tomorrow.
Could it be done before noon?
How'd you do?
Let's check out the question one more time.
What does the woman want Jonas to do?
A. Buy her some coffee.
B. Do a presentation next week.
Or C.
答えは
C. Make slides before noon
質問は
女性はジョナスに何をしてほしい?
A. 彼女にコーヒーを買う
B. 来週プレゼンをする
C. お昼までにスライドを作る
答えはC. お昼までにスライドを作る
となります
Alright, and last up is Thursday's dialogue.
First, let's check out the question.
何が起こるかを教えて下さい。
A. 雨が降る。
B. シホはアクターになる。
C. ドッグはシホにマッサージをする。
では、行きましょう。
ドッグ、雨が降るの閉まったの?
はい、シホ。窓は守られている。
ありがとう。台風は強いです。
Hey, can you take a look at this?
What's up?
It's this email.
I can't tell whether this is a real message or not.
What do you mean?
It was sent by a person named Arnold Sylvester.
The famous actor?
It seems like it.
But I don't know if it's the same person or not.
He wants to visit our island.
Alright, how did you do?
Let's check out that question one more time
What is likely to happen?
A. A storm will come
B. Shiho will become an actor
C. Doug will give Shiho a massage
答えは
A. A storm will come
質問は何が起こりそう?
A. 嵐が来る
B. シホは俳優になる
C. ダグはシホにマッサージをする
答えはA 嵐が来るとなります
さあリスリングチャレンジできばいかがでしたでしょうか
徐々にできるようになってきたという喜びの声をいくつかいただきましたよ
今週練習した表現を使って会話の実践練習をしましょう
新企画の進捗状況が明日の会議の議題となりました 部下に以前報告を頼んでいた内容です
部下にそのリポートを朝一で提出するように指示してください 例えば
先日新しいプロジェクトの進捗報告書を提出するようにお願いしましたね 覚えていますか
そのリポートを明日の朝一に私の机に置いてほしいのです 明日の会議の議題になるので
さあヒントを差し上げていきましょう 進捗報告書これはプログレスリポートとおっしゃってみてください
提出するこれはサブメットという動詞が使えます 議題はアジェンダとなります
先日新しいプロジェクトの進捗報告書を提出するようにお願いしましたね 覚えていますかそのリポートを明日の朝一に私の机に置いてほしいのです
明日の会議の議題になるので
など
さあ部下を呼び止めますよ
Yes
あなたならどう言いますか
それではここでローザさんの答えを聞きましょう
では内容を順番に確認します
Asked
以下はto不定詞を用いた目的語説明型
youがsubmit〜に進むように頼んだということ
最初の文はレッスン131で同様の文を重ねて学習しています
すぐにできたのではないでしょうか
繰り返し学習大切ですよ
それではローゾーさんの答えをもう一度聞きましょう
では今の答えを一文ずつリピートしましょう
The other day I asked you to submit a progress report for the new project.
I want that report on my desk first thing tomorrow morning
That will be on the agenda for tomorrow's meeting
Alright, let's move on to the next situation
Imagine this
定年後の趣味で山小屋を建てようと思っているあなた 経験皆無のあなたを友人が心配しています応答してください
例えば素人にとって山小屋を建てるのはとても大変なのは知っているよ でも一人でやってみたいんだ
もし助けが必要なら連絡するよなど それではヒントです
素人これはアマチュアとおっしゃってみてください
素人にとって山小屋を建てるのはとても大変なのは知っているよ でも一人でやってみたいんだ
もし助けが必要なら連絡するよなど さあ友人にこう聞かれますよ
あなたならどう言いますか
それではここでデイビッドさんの答えを聞きましょう
では内容を順番に確認します
No以下はリポート文。Noの後ろに節を続けます。
Building a cabinと動詞ing形を主語にするこの形。もう慣れていただけましたか?
By myselfは一人で。周りには誰もいないことがイメージされています。
I'll let you know if I need help.
Letを用いた目的語説明型。YouがNoすることをLet、許すことをLet。
それではデイビッドさんの答えをもう一度聞きましょう
では今の答えを一文ずつリピートしましょう
But I'd like to try to do it by myself
役に立てるかどうか教えてあげるよ。
テーネンゴの住みか。
みなさん、キャビンを建てたことはありますか?
キャビン?
もしかしたら、現実のキャビンではなく、小さなトイブロックのようなもの?
I've built a roof cover for my horses so far, but not by myself.
なるほど。いやいや、退職後に何をするのかっていうのは楽しみですよね。
さあ、それでは今日はこのへんで。
バイバイ。